all right what is up guys welcome back
to another set and forget podcast so you
guys already know we're gonna start the
series of my psychology golden ticket to
become a full-time trader so i'll be
completely honest this is not video
number one one because i'm like
extremely busy more than i could like
ever imagine i'm working on so many
things that like i'm figuring out right
now kind of how to manage any everything
and also the way that i wanted to
structure the psychology series i wanted
to have a structure like i wanted each
video to be organized and for
transparency i haven't organized it yet
but this video is going to be kind of
like a sneak peek of what to expect this
is basically going to be
intro to an intro to an intro because
this video was going to come later on in
the series but i'm just gonna give it to
you guys now because it's really very
very very very relevant to what i think
that is happening right now in the
markets with the majority of the traders
that i have gotten dms on instagram and
just a lot of comments um you know like
and you can you know it's gonna be it's
gonna make a little bit more sense um
later on in the video but um this is
going to be very relevant to what is
happening currently right now so you
guys already know if you guys are new to
the channel make sure to like comment
and subscribe turn on notifications i
drop videos every tuesday and friday
and this video is going to be probably a
little bit funny um i'm pretty good with
the analogies or so i believe and you
know your guys's feedback is going to
mean everything so this video is going
to be related with fear fomo
fear of missing out right so
right now we're experiencing um our
we're closing q2 right so i have gotten
several dms that people they have just
all right because the last
six weeks have been phenomenal right the
last six weeks um right now we're
currently on an eight week winning
streak on the signal group and the last
six weeks for everybody and just the
trading world has been capitalizing if
you go look at the markets when i posted
this video six weeks ago the microsoft
has been giving crazy great
opportunities i've been getting many dms
a bunch of traders have passed level up
challenges or they have just palace a
challenge verification they either
funded whatever the case is happening
right so i've gotten several dms of
traders that are oh bro
four weeks ago i passed my challenge
now this week or last week i failed my
verification or i passed my challenge
and verification and now i failed my
funding and this is something you guys
need to understand and this is going to
implement now with fomo and it's going
to make so much sense towards the middle
ending of this video
due to the fact that we are just coming
off some crazy banger weeks you need to
understand you can't come with that same
energy every single week because it
doesn't like the markets don't determine
your trades based off of your energy
they're gonna determine your trades
based off of the probabilities the
markets give you the market's not giving
you any probabilities you don't take a
trade it's very simple right so let me
explain to you a little bit right
trading with high
trading with the markets that are giving
you high probability setups are markets
that are just fire they're just giving
you hella opportunities it's very much
like surfing so
i know that might sound a little
confusing for those of you guys that are
about to click off in the video or be
like oh this guy's fried what the hell
is he saying trust me listen it's gonna
make sense so these guys i want to put
some notes down it's going to make so
much sense in a little bit
trading is very much like surfing what
the hell do i mean
let me explain
when you're going to go trade in the
markets
ideally you want to trade with the trend
the trend is your friend if the market
is bullish you're looking to buy if the
market is bearish you're looking to sell
very simple if you're trying to do
anything in between that
sorry buddy you're just not gonna make
it in the long run it's just not gonna
happen for you it's like when bitcoin is
now dropping you're not buying bro you
want to be selling and when bitcoin is
bullish you want to be buying you don't
want to be trying to predict the top you
don't want to be predicting the bottom
the trend is your friend right when it
comes to serving it's very much the same
if you go out to ocean you know ocean um
south beach or wherever you surf in
hawaii or kali where wherever you surf
if there's hella waves coming out but
you're getting on your board and you're
surfing ideally you would want to get
the wave that takes you from the buoys
you know the buoys that are way out
there say yo you can't pass that zone
because you can't swim yeah those buoys
if you're if you're getting on a wave
from there all the way to the shore
that's your purpose your purpose is to
surf the whole entire weight you don't
want to catch that little retracement
wave that kind of makes the big wave i
hope that makes sense
putting it into analogy when it comes to
the markets there's going to be little
four-hour trends that create the
retracement for the overall bigger
weekly and daily move right so you don't
want to be catching that little push
that's gonna you know obviously go and
crash the wave against you so what i
mean that surfing is very similar to
trading it is due to the fact that you
are both going with the trend when
you're trading you're going with the
trend when you're surfing you're going
with the waves if the waves are going to
the shore you're trying to ride the wave
to the shore so when you're surfing you
obviously understand that there's going
to be some days that there's some fire
you know waves that there's a lot of
wind there's a lot of current there's a
hurricane coming or whatever whatever is
going on that there's a lot of waves
being created so that means you're out
there on your board you're [__]
catching waves from the you know
wherever the wave is all the way to the
shore it feels good right because this
is what you do you're a surfer and you
know you're you're right you're right in
the wave you're doing your thing right
but there's going to be times where
there's just nothing where you go out to
the beach you drive all the way to the
beach you drive all the way over there
you get off on your board you put on
your wetsuit you do whatever you got to
do you pull up to the sand and you're
like damn
there's no waves what are you going to
do are you going to just
force there to be a wave are you just
going to go out there in the ocean and
try to make something out of nothing
probably not you're probably going to
get in your car and leave because
there's nothing for you to do there
right
it's the same thing when it comes to the
markets if you
wake up in the morning you drink your
coffee do your meditation whatever you
do before you trade you come to the
markets you do your analysis and there's
no trades because the market isn't
bullish or bearish the market isn't
trending it's just consolidating it's
all over the place you simply get up and
leave
and that's kind of what has been
happening in these past two weeks we're
coming off some beautiful trending moves
and a lot of traders coming in with that
same energy to these other weeks where
there's nothing happening you're just
coming off the best waves of your life
[__] 20 foot waves i don't even know
if that's like a thing or whatever but
you're coming off these huge waves that
are taking you from there all the way to
the shore
and now you're coming to the to the
ocean again and there's nothing so
you're like mad at that point not at the
ocean but you're mad at yourself like
now at this point you don't feel good
now you're trying to justify your role
as a surfer because you have to be
surfing if not you don't feel content
with yourself because you're not getting
the satisfaction of riding the wave to
the shore so at this point you're gonna
try to wait for a boat to pass by and
make a little wave and then go out there
and just try to ride that or you're
gonna
drive to another spa and at this point
you're not doing what you're supposed to
do and it's just pull up to the ocean
and let the waves give you the
opportunity to surf it you're trying to
make something out of nothing saying
into the markets the market's not giving
you an opportunity to take a high
probability setup so you're literally
trying to make something out of nothing
you're looking at the four hour four
hour doesn't look good now you know what
let me go down to the one hour the one
hour doesn't look good let me see if the
30 minute looks clean at the 15 minute
and what you're doing is you're just
trying to make something out of nothing
when you look at it on the bigger scale
when you look at the weekly or the daily
but we're in the same 20 40 50 pip range
why are you trying to force something
making something out of nothing and yes
don't get me wrong you can probably
catch those little moves those little 5
10 15 pip trades if you want but ideally
you know you're gonna probably not get
much money out of it because you got to
pay broker
uh commissions uh spreads whatever the k
like these are just fees that you gotta
pick unless you're using the broker that
i'm using if you guys wanna know more
about it link in the description below
raw spreads zero commissions
um but it's like if you're gonna go surf
you know when you go surfing there's
nothing like this literally like a plate
the ocean has no waves but there's some
little little ant waves at the shore
it's like you're trying to write that
like there's nothing for you to do there
right so this is the point
where it's a make or break for a lot of
traders probably not for a lot of
surfers because i'm sure surfers know
they got it you they'll just come back
another day but this is the point where
what do you do are you gonna go out
there and probably get eaten by a shark
because there's nothing going on you're
gonna go out into the market go trade
gonna go lose your money or are you
gonna simply just
sit down on the sand
put your surfboard down and wait for
something to happen or are you gonna use
this time in your advantage so when you
come back to surf again you are a better
surfer than what you would have been
before so what do i mean by that bro if
you're not surfing go wax your board go
get a new wetsuit go hit the gym go do
whatever surfer does when they're not
surfing bro if there's nothing going on
in the markets right now if it's not
trending use this time to back test
re-analyze your trades
uh read a book hit the gym like get do
something that's when you come back into
the mark when you go back into the
charts you're going to be more focused
than you are before and this is where a
lot of traders need to understand their
role your role is to take a trade when
the market gives you the opportunity
your role as a surfer is to ride a wave
when the ocean gives you a wave
simply because there's no longer a wave
for the day for the three days for the
week whatever the case that doesn't mean
you're not a surfer you're just
your role isn't to be implemented right
now so you just come back when it's
ready
just because you're not trading for
three four five six seven eight days
doesn't mean you're not a trader anymore
you're just simply waiting for your role
to come back and kick in and that's when
the market is making higher highs higher
lows trending and this is where you
become a threat to the markets why
because you no longer need to
feel a need to be in front of the charts
to justify your role you don't need you
don't need to be involved in the markets
to have a purpose to be a trader your
purpose to be a trader is to take a
trade whenever it makes sense it's that
simple you don't have to be there every
single day in order for you to justify
who you are free to get the satisfaction
let me tell you it feels good when you
get that trade it feels good when you
get that new higher high push and you
get the whole entire move it feels good
riding the wave from the wherever to the
shore i've never surfed in my life but i
feel like this is a damn good analogy so
to my point is that i'm sure it feels
good to do that right maybe one day i'll
learn to surf but
you know that that's what you do so when
you're gonna do what you're gonna do
it's that simple you're not gonna feel
bad or you're not gonna feel this fomo
because you're not on a wave
trust me if you were busy this week
simply because you were working or
whatever the case you were doing and you
weren't riding a wave
you know that when you come back
whenever you come back the ocean has to
give you a wave that's just what the
ocean does and when it gives it to you
you take it you're not gonna care damn
bro last week there was a 20-foot wave
for oh [__] dude i hate my life dude i
guarantee you it's gonna come again
probably not 20 maybe 18 feet i don't
even know that's a real size of a wave
but to my point is that the market's
gonna the ocean is going to give you a
new opportunity same thing with the
market if you were sleeping or you
weren't looking at the charts if you
were working or whatever excuse you want
to make that you didn't catch that trade
bro that's cool don't get fomo man the
market is gonna give you another
opportunity because that's just what the
market does
it's really that simple once you
understand this every video from this
point on is gonna honestly get you guys
one closer to becoming a profitable
trader and it is going to be the golden
ticket for you guys to become successful
in the markets if you guys found this
video helpful useful if i sound like a
total buffoon or like a clown talking
about this surfing and analogy to the
markets let me know in the comments if
you found the fire if you honestly think
this kind of helped you guys and it made
a lot more sense i could go into a lot
more depth but i want to save it for the
series this is just kind of like a
little introduction to what to expect in
the further videos so you guys found
this video firing and help drop a set
and forget down below in the comments or
just say something i don't know you guys
feedback means crazy we're getting 20 30
000 views on these podcasts thousand
comments and like it honestly means a
lot to me because it shows like i know
all this hard work that i'm putting into
these videos generally helps you guys
and you guys like it so you guys
feedback just means more than everything
um new update yes i got an app coming
out for you guys that didn't know i have
an app i got a i don't know what i'm
going to name it yet or what is going to
go down but it's it's going to literally
be a free app it's going to be better
than instagram like you're not gonna be
wasting time searching through instagram
being distracted same way how i kind of
post a bunch of trade ideas on my
instagram stories i'm gonna do the same
thing within the app so it's gonna be
strictly trader um dominated it's gonna
be just prioritized to just traders i
have a free app coming very soon um yeah
signals still eight week winning streak
we're catching all these waves surfing
to the store now okay so if you're gonna
join the waiting list of the signals
make sure to click the link in the
description below and if you guys found
this video useful again just let me know
in the comments i i'm very excited for
this series to come out i'm just yes i'm
still going to be doing the podcast as
usual but i kind of want to show you
guys a little introduction and um to
what to expect from the psychology
videos and i felt like this is a good
video to kind of give you guys the
proper
um
proper foundation
to what to expect in the next series due
to what is currently happening right now
in the markets based off of you know the
the community that i see that they're
struggling with so i hope this video has
helped you guys and i'll see you guys in
the next video